<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>FOSS on ALiAS Writes</title><link>http://asetalias.in/blog/tags/foss/</link><description>Recent content in FOSS on ALiAS Writes</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2019 10:10:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://asetalias.in/blog/tags/foss/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Dabbling with React @ React India 2019: A Tweet story</title><link>http://asetalias.in/blog/post/reactindia2019-vipulgupta2048/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2019 10:10:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://asetalias.in/blog/post/reactindia2019-vipulgupta2048/</guid><description>Lush green trees, monsoon weather, soul cooling winds coming from the tumultuous waters of the beach where sounds of waves splashing over the dry sand can be heard by people walking by. Now, just imagine a tech conference on a piece of software that powers almost half of the web today at the place that I just described. How could you stop yourself? I couldn&amp;rsquo;t. Here&amp;rsquo;s a brief twitter story of my adventures at React India.</description></item><item><title>My journey with ALiAS : From a commit to the community</title><link>http://asetalias.in/blog/post/animesh-alias-journey/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://asetalias.in/blog/post/animesh-alias-journey/</guid><description>Four years of college life in Amity, during which I went through a lot of ups and downs, nailed it at sometimes while screwed it at some (yeah college life plays both ways). Being extremely passionate about computers, I always looked for learning opportunities in this field outside of the curriculum. But neither the technical clubs nor events could fulfill the quest, as they meant nothing more than ways to get some certificates or to bunk classes.</description></item><item><title>ALiAS does it again: Report on our GSoC AMA program</title><link>http://asetalias.in/blog/post/aliasama/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://asetalias.in/blog/post/aliasama/</guid><description>ALiAS is the largest open-source community at Amity University and as one of the founding member of our small 500+ active member community nothing makes me happier than writing about it and looking back on our accomplishments, failures and new initiatives.
Update 2019 All accepted students from ALiAS have successfully completed their projects for GSoC 2019. Details are as follows.
Ayush Bhardwaj, GSoC Archive link. Reach him @ LinkedIn, Twitter, Email: classicayush@gmail.</description></item></channel></rss>