<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on ALiAS Writes</title><link>http://asetalias.in/blog/post/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on ALiAS Writes</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://asetalias.in/blog/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Online Hackathon : An Experiment</title><link>http://asetalias.in/blog/post/first-online-hackathon-akshat/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://asetalias.in/blog/post/first-online-hackathon-akshat/</guid><description>The first image which comes to a beginner&amp;rsquo;s mind on hearing the word Hackathon is a group of people with professional ethical hacking skills who are racing towards a specific goal to win in a competition, even I thought similarly until my fellows from ALiAS helped me to sort it out.
In layman terms, a Hackathon is just a coding competition where people, individually or in groups, work upon building a useful project out of a list of problem-statements or a theme with the help of various mentors present at the venue.</description></item><item><title>Dabbling with React @ React India 2019: A Tweet story</title><link>http://asetalias.in/blog/post/reactindia2019-vipulgupta2048/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2019 10:10:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://asetalias.in/blog/post/reactindia2019-vipulgupta2048/</guid><description>Lush green trees, monsoon weather, soul cooling winds coming from the tumultuous waters of the beach where sounds of waves splashing over the dry sand can be heard by people walking by. Now, just imagine a tech conference on a piece of software that powers almost half of the web today at the place that I just described. How could you stop yourself? I couldn&amp;rsquo;t. Here&amp;rsquo;s a brief twitter story of my adventures at React India.</description></item><item><title>My journey with ALiAS : From a commit to the community</title><link>http://asetalias.in/blog/post/animesh-alias-journey/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://asetalias.in/blog/post/animesh-alias-journey/</guid><description>Four years of college life in Amity, during which I went through a lot of ups and downs, nailed it at sometimes while screwed it at some (yeah college life plays both ways). Being extremely passionate about computers, I always looked for learning opportunities in this field outside of the curriculum. But neither the technical clubs nor events could fulfill the quest, as they meant nothing more than ways to get some certificates or to bunk classes.</description></item><item><title>The Future is Rust(y)?</title><link>http://asetalias.in/blog/post/future-with-rust/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://asetalias.in/blog/post/future-with-rust/</guid><description>Rust is the system programming language for the future. Quite a presumptuous statement, said my confreres. I would be inclined to agree with them but for the experience of the agony of using C.
“Having been tortured by C during my years of wiring security-critical software, I don’t think I exaggerate when I compare programming in it with walking through a minefield.” by Ivan Ristic, Founder of SSL Labs</description></item><item><title>Getting Started With Flutter</title><link>http://asetalias.in/blog/post/getting-started-with-flutter/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://asetalias.in/blog/post/getting-started-with-flutter/</guid><description>Flutter is Google’s portable UI toolkit for building beautiful, natively-compiled applications for mobile, web, and desktop from a single codebase.
More on Flutter&amp;hellip; According to me, Flutter has a very bright future ahead as Google is using Flutter for the development of their own apps. It has very expressive and Flexible UI and it is famous for its Native Performance. The main challenge is that cross-platform development can be problematic. In recent years we have seen the emergence of various mobile frameworks like React Native and AngularJS that help make it easier for the developers.</description></item><item><title>Becoming a Debian Maintainer in 90 days!</title><link>http://asetalias.in/blog/post/build-commit-dput/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2019 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://asetalias.in/blog/post/build-commit-dput/</guid><description>NOTE: I know this should have been posted long, long back :(
However, life happened and I couldn&amp;rsquo;t. Anyway, here it goes..
I started contributing to open source around a year back and on 1st January 2019 to Debian, specifically (wasn&amp;rsquo;t really a new year resolution, though :P).
I&amp;rsquo;ll be honest here. The reason behind taking the &amp;ldquo;Debian road&amp;rdquo; was solely to distract myself from the mental abuse I was going through.</description></item><item><title>ALiAS does it again: Report on our GSoC AMA program</title><link>http://asetalias.in/blog/post/aliasama/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://asetalias.in/blog/post/aliasama/</guid><description>ALiAS is the largest open-source community at Amity University and as one of the founding member of our small 500+ active member community nothing makes me happier than writing about it and looking back on our accomplishments, failures and new initiatives.
Update 2019 All accepted students from ALiAS have successfully completed their projects for GSoC 2019. Details are as follows.
Ayush Bhardwaj, GSoC Archive link. Reach him @ LinkedIn, Twitter, Email: classicayush@gmail.</description></item><item><title>Community Unpacked</title><link>http://asetalias.in/blog/post/alias-lucknow-journey-akshat/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://asetalias.in/blog/post/alias-lucknow-journey-akshat/</guid><description>The first time, getting introduced to the world of development, I was amazed! exploring a number of technologies in the initial days of my B.Tech just for the sake of knowledge and after working on few of them at last chose, web development as my primary field.
One of my classmate suggested me to join ALiAS, a coding community of Amity University, Noida which was the main branch of our college.</description></item><item><title>A Guide to Flashing Custom ROMs [Android]</title><link>http://asetalias.in/blog/post/flash_custom_rom/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://asetalias.in/blog/post/flash_custom_rom/</guid><description>(Warning: The following process might brick your device.)
To start with, you should have an unlocked bootloader.
For Xiaomi devices refer to the following link : Click-Here
Follow the process to unlock your phone&amp;rsquo;s bootloader. (Xiaomi takes 3 days to process your request to unlock your bootloader.)
Download ADB(Android Debug Bridge) and Fastboot files from this link: Click-Here
A .zip file for Windows will be downloaded. Extract these files to a folder.</description></item><item><title>ALiAS : My first open-source community</title><link>http://asetalias.in/blog/post/journey-with-open-source-community/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://asetalias.in/blog/post/journey-with-open-source-community/</guid><description>How and when it all started? I started my college here at Amity in 2017 till then I was completely unaware of how the communities work. Few days passed, I started exploring events in colleges than one of my friends told me about ALiAS also known as (Amity Linux Assistance Sapience). He told me that there is something also known as Open-Source and this community supports open source and this community is one of its kind in the college.</description></item><item><title>Data Science: A Beginner's Roadmap</title><link>http://asetalias.in/blog/post/datascience/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://asetalias.in/blog/post/datascience/</guid><description>What is the hype about this buzz word &amp;ldquo;Data Science&amp;rdquo;? Data science is a tool that turns data into real-world actions. These include machine learning, database technologies, statistics, programming, and domain-specific technologies. It&amp;rsquo;s about collecting, analyzing, communicating and modeling the data around us in a productive way. Data science includes, Experimentation, Exploratory analysis, analytics,business intelligence, etc and the most popular ones are Machine Learning and AI. Machine learning and AI dominates because of the trends that all the new companies and startups want to establish their structure or base.</description></item><item><title>How to write like you have a brain on ALiAS Writes by the creators</title><link>http://asetalias.in/blog/post/tutorial-post-for-kids/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://asetalias.in/blog/post/tutorial-post-for-kids/</guid><description>Why should I join the club? Join the club and which is just not about certificates or designation(s): Stand out of crowd and learn unique skills from people already working in the industry! Find like minded Delhi/NCR Tech Communities. Find mentors for GSoC Learn Linux, Android, Networking, etc. There is no limit on how much and what you can learn! Chance to find Interships under our Alumni. ALiAS welcomes each and every student of amity irrespective of their department.</description></item></channel></rss>