<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>ALiAS on ALiAS Writes</title><link>http://asetalias.in/blog/tags/alias/</link><description>Recent content in ALiAS on ALiAS Writes</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://asetalias.in/blog/tags/alias/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>My journey with ALiAS : From a commit to the community</title><link>http://asetalias.in/blog/post/animesh-alias-journey/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://asetalias.in/blog/post/animesh-alias-journey/</guid><description>Four years of college life in Amity, during which I went through a lot of ups and downs, nailed it at sometimes while screwed it at some (yeah college life plays both ways). Being extremely passionate about computers, I always looked for learning opportunities in this field outside of the curriculum. But neither the technical clubs nor events could fulfill the quest, as they meant nothing more than ways to get some certificates or to bunk classes.</description></item><item><title>Community Unpacked</title><link>http://asetalias.in/blog/post/alias-lucknow-journey-akshat/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://asetalias.in/blog/post/alias-lucknow-journey-akshat/</guid><description>The first time, getting introduced to the world of development, I was amazed! exploring a number of technologies in the initial days of my B.Tech just for the sake of knowledge and after working on few of them at last chose, web development as my primary field.
One of my classmate suggested me to join ALiAS, a coding community of Amity University, Noida which was the main branch of our college.</description></item><item><title>ALiAS : My first open-source community</title><link>http://asetalias.in/blog/post/journey-with-open-source-community/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://asetalias.in/blog/post/journey-with-open-source-community/</guid><description>How and when it all started? I started my college here at Amity in 2017 till then I was completely unaware of how the communities work. Few days passed, I started exploring events in colleges than one of my friends told me about ALiAS also known as (Amity Linux Assistance Sapience). He told me that there is something also known as Open-Source and this community supports open source and this community is one of its kind in the college.</description></item></channel></rss>