<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Python on ALiAS Writes</title><link>http://asetalias.in/blog/tags/python/</link><description>Recent content in Python on ALiAS Writes</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://asetalias.in/blog/tags/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Online Hackathon : An Experiment</title><link>http://asetalias.in/blog/post/first-online-hackathon-akshat/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://asetalias.in/blog/post/first-online-hackathon-akshat/</guid><description>The first image which comes to a beginner&amp;rsquo;s mind on hearing the word Hackathon is a group of people with professional ethical hacking skills who are racing towards a specific goal to win in a competition, even I thought similarly until my fellows from ALiAS helped me to sort it out.
In layman terms, a Hackathon is just a coding competition where people, individually or in groups, work upon building a useful project out of a list of problem-statements or a theme with the help of various mentors present at the venue.</description></item><item><title>Data Science: A Beginner's Roadmap</title><link>http://asetalias.in/blog/post/datascience/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://asetalias.in/blog/post/datascience/</guid><description>What is the hype about this buzz word &amp;ldquo;Data Science&amp;rdquo;? Data science is a tool that turns data into real-world actions. These include machine learning, database technologies, statistics, programming, and domain-specific technologies. It&amp;rsquo;s about collecting, analyzing, communicating and modeling the data around us in a productive way. Data science includes, Experimentation, Exploratory analysis, analytics,business intelligence, etc and the most popular ones are Machine Learning and AI. Machine learning and AI dominates because of the trends that all the new companies and startups want to establish their structure or base.</description></item></channel></rss>